Md. Fardim Sufian Roney

Dhaka, Bangladesh - +8801324369906 – fardim-roney1011010@gmail.com - linkedin.com/in/fardim-roney - grabcad.com/fardim-1

June 03, 2021

Bangladesh Honda Pvt. Ltd.

Monem Business District, East Tower (10th floor), 111, Bir Uttam C. R. Dutta Road, Karwanbazar, Dhaka–1205, Bangladesh.

Dear Hiring Manager,

As an Industrial Engineer with more than 2 years of experience in the manufacturing industry, I learned that the best way to achieve success was to motivate the resources I had with well-defined objectives and empowerment. During my previous role at Refrigerator R&D in WALTON GROUP, I was tasked with designing, developing & producing models. Besides, I worked on a team that was comprised of many different disciplines, which meant I needed to be cognizant of their respective expertise and know when to yield to their discretion.

I've heard of your reputation in the industry, and I would be proud to work for a company with such an excellent track record and a strong example of leadership in the industry. I have a senior that works in the Executive Engine Assembly department, and he told me that the culture here is top-notch. Based on his assessment and encouragement, I think that I would fit in perfectly with the team here to make an immediate impact.

I have the ability to find my niche within a group and support everyone's efforts. For example, my last job involved a lot of team projects. I was always able to recognize my teammates' skills, and delegated tasks that fit each person's skills. I know this job involves lots of teamwork and group projects, and I know this is a work style in which I excel.

My primary objective in my career is to gain additional certifications and stronger leadership experience so that I can finally run and move on to my team. The knowledge and experience I will gain from working with your team will give me the tools to be successful in the field and help me to reach my goals. In my last job, I was involved in various innovations, including ways to improve teamwork. Not only can I bring these ideas with me, but I am also a keen proponent of innovation in general as I believe it drives progress.

For more information regarding my qualifications, see my resume. I would greatly appreciate an opportunity to discuss this in more detail. Thank you for considering my application.

Sincerely,

Md. Fardim Sufian Roney

MD. FARDIM SUFIAN RONEY

Contact: +8801324369906

Address: Mohammadpur, Dhaka, Bangladesh Gmail: fardimroney1011010@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/fardim-roney GrabCAD: grabcad.com/fardim-1



Career Summary

Dedicated and detail-oriented experiences with 2+ years of designing, developing SOPs, subsequent time studies, motion studies, optimizing productivity, quality, and cost. Worked directly with R&D, and production line to define KPIs for each new production line and develop means of collecting and analyzing data. Strives to contribute exceptional experiences and leadership abilities to benefit a company in its designated sectors.

Core Proficiencies

- AUTOCAD - CATIA - LINGO - C - PLANNING - SIMULATION - SOLIDWORK - ANSYS - R - PYTHON - DESIGN - PRODUCTION

- CREO - TORA - MINITAB - FORTRAN - ASSEMBLY

Professional Experiences

Organization: Andong National University Designation: Graduate Research Assistant

Location: Andong, Gyeongsangbuk-do, South Korea **Duration:** (September 2018 – February 2021)

- Optimally designed experimental enabling tools (Drilling device, Bending device, Heater attachments).
- As a lab manager, lab activities and machinery were properly supervised.
- Research and 3 different projects have been performed at the designated times.

Accomplishments

• Established an optimal recycling process for metal-CFRP hybrid structure (Recycling rates > 95%)

Organization: WALTON HI-TECH INDUSTRIES LTD Designation: Senior Assistant General Manager

Location: Chandra, Kaliakoir, Bangladesh **Duration:** (August 2015 – August 2017)

- Product Design (Door liner, Gasket, sheet metal parts), BOM preparation, system development for (50L, 112L, 120L) refrigerators.
- Prepared the journal of 2D CAD drawing for each product and component.
- Ensured the production of sheet metal, casting section to avoid 0% offset of production.
- Investigated results with 100% optimized use of inventory management and warehouses.
- Trained 20 personnel in new refrigerator production processes and provided manuals.
- Prepared documentation of processes of 3 different refrigerators and prepare production reports.
- Managed own team, identifying and addressing performance issues as they arise.
- Collaborated with the engineering and marketing department on product feasibility.
- NUSDAT-UTS Technical Authority on volume measurement and certification of refrigerators.
- Confirmed the refrigerator sticker designs, and article for an online journal.

Accomplishments

- Successfully introduced wine coolers (50L, 112L, 120L refrigerators) to the market.
- Robust product design and development with minimal use of raw materials.
- 5S implementation within the work area and process.

Organization: SQ GROUP Designation: Executive

Location: Valuka, Mymensingh **Duration:** (June 2015 – July 2015)

Precisely surveyed the line performance, change effectiveness, time, and motion studies of 30 operators.

- Investigated capability Studies, production Studies, PDCA Cycle, waste Reduction of 7.
- Controlled 100% inputs, outputs, and hourly production and control of sound data retention.
- Tracked low-performing operators (≤ 70%), failure of the operation, operating bulletin/layout.
- Debriefed and discussed the layout of 27 lines with the responsible floor and technical team.

Accomplishments

- The robust design of workstations, optimizing working space (>10% than previous).
- Achieved >90% goal of the balanced process and production planning.

Training

- Technical Tour Meghna Cement Industry, Mongla, Khulna -- Observation of Various Types of Conveyors, Structural designs, functions, and control system of conveyor, Packaging system of cement.
- 2nd Workshop on "Advanced Engineering Management An Industrial Engineering Approach", Supply Chain Management, Innovative Production Management, Quality Management, Lean Manufacturing.

Certifications

- Coursera Introduction to Supply Chain Finance & Blockchain Technology
- Coursera Supply chain management: Be global
- Coursera Supply Chain Logistics

Educational Attainments

- M.Sc. in Mechanical Design Engineering from Andong National University, South Korea with CGPA 4.19.
- B.Sc. in Industrial and Production Engineering (IPE) from Khulna University of Engineering & Technology (KUET) with CGPA 2.95.
- H.S.C. in Science from Cantonment Public School and College, Saidpur, Nilphamari with GPA 5.00.
- S.S.C. in Science from Cantonment Public School and College, Saidpur, Nilphamari with GPA 5.00.

Projects

- M.Sc. Establishment of recycling process for metal-CFRP hybrid structures (Achievement: Recycling Rates > 95%).
- B.Sc. Analysis and Reduction of Casting Defects by Design of Experiment (DoE) and Casting Simulation Technique (Achievement: Defects reduction > 50%, Improvement in design).
- B.Sc. Comparative Analysis of Ahp and Fuzzy Ahp Models For Multi-criteria Inventory Classification.

Extra-Curricular activities

 Executive member and instructor of Caders (Designing club) for 2D and 3D design at Khulna University of Engineering and Technology (KUET).

Interest Area

Supply Chain Management	Planning	System Development	Marketing
Total Quality Management	Logistics	Production	Manufacturing

Personal Information

Date of Birth: 4th November 1993; Nationality: Bangladeshi; Passport No.: BR0287454; Marital Status: Single